We will begin this exercise with a three -to -one method.
Find a comfortable sitting position.
Close your eyes.
Take a deep breath. And while exhaling, mentally repeat and
visualize the number three, three times.
Level three is for physical relaxation, where you can learn to
relax from head to toes in a matter of seconds.
To help you learn to relax physically at Level 3, I am
going to direct your attention to different parts of your body.
Concentrate your sense of awareness on your scalp, the skin that
covers your head.
You will detect a fine vibration, a tingling sensation, a
feeling of warmth caused by circulation.
Now release and completely relax all tensions and ligament
pressures from this part of your head and place it in a
deep state of relaxation that will grow deeper and deeper as we
continue. you.
Concentrate your sense of awareness on your forehead, the skin
that covers your forehead.
You will detect a fine vibration, a tingling sensation,
a feeling of warmth caused by circulation.
now release and completely relax all tensions and ligament
pressures from this part of your head
and place it in a deep state of relaxation
that will grow deeper and deeper as we continue
concentrate Concentrate your sense of awareness on your eyelids
and the tissue surrounding your eyes.
You will detect a fine vibration, a tingling sensation, a
feeling of warmth caused by circulation.
Now release and relax
all tensions and ligament pressures from this part of your head
and place it in a deep state of relaxation
that will grow deeper and deeper as we continue.
Concentrate your sense of awareness on your face, the skin
covering your cheeks.
You will detect a fine vibration, a tingling sensation, a
feeling of warmth caused by circulation.
Now release and completely relax all tensions and ligament
pressures from this part of your head
and place it in a deep state of relaxation
that will grow deeper and deeper as we continue. in you.
Concentrate on the outer portion of your throat,
throat, the skin covering your throat area.
You will detect a fine vibration, a tingling sensation, a
feeling of warmth caused by circulation.
Now release and completely relax all tensions and ligament
pressures from this part of your body and place it in a
deep state of relaxation that will grow deeper and deeper as we
continue. you.
Concentrate within the throat area.
And relax all tensions and ligament pressures from this part of
your body and place it in In a deep state of relaxation,
going deeper and deeper every time.
Concentrate on your shoulders.
Feel your clothing in contact with your body.
Feel the skin and the vibration of the skin covering this part
of your body.
Relax all tensions and ligament pressures and to place your
shoulders in a deep state state of relaxation, going deeper and
deeper every time.
Concentrate on your chest.
Feel your clothing in contact with this part of your body.
Feel the skin, and the vibration of your skin covering your
chest.
Relax all tensions and ligament pressures, and place your chest
in a deep state of relaxation, going deeper and deeper every
time.
Concentrate within the chest area.
Relax all organs.
Relax all glands, relax all tissues, including the cells
themselves, and cause them to function in a rhythmic, healthy
manner.
Concentrate on your abdomen.
Feel the clothing in contact with this part of your body.
Feel the skin and the vibration of the skin covering your
abdomen.
Relax all tensions and ligament pressures and place your abdomen
in a deep state of relaxation going deeper and deeper every
time.
Concentrate within the abdominal area.
Relax all organs.
Relax all glands. hands, relax all tissues, including the cells
themselves, and cause them to function in in a rhythmic, healthy
manner.
Concentrate on your thighs.
Feel the clothing in contact with this part of your body.
Feel the skin and the vibration of your skin covering your
thighs.
Relax all tensions and ligament pressures and place your thighs
in a deep state of relaxation, going deeper and deeper every
time.
Sense the vibrations at the bones within the thighs.
By now these vibrations are easily detectable.
concentrate on your knees
feel the skin and the vibration of your skin covering the knees
Relax all tensions and ligament pressures, and place your knees
in a deep state of relaxation, going deeper and deeper every
time.
Concentrate on your calves.
Feel the skin and the vibration of the skin covering your
calves.
Relax all tensions and ligament pressures
and place these parts of your body in a deep state of
relaxation,
going deeper and deeper Deeper, every time.
To enter a deeper, healthier level of mind, concentrate on your
toes.
Enter a deeper, healthier level of mind.
To enter a deeper, healthier level of mind, concentrate on the
soles of your feet.
feet.
Enter a deeper, healthier level of mind.
To enter a deeper, healthier level of mind, concentrate on the
heels of your feet.
8. Enter a deeper, healthier level of mind.
9. Now cause your feet to feel as though they do not
belong to your body.
Your feet feel as though they do not belong to your body.
Your feet, ankles, calves, and knees feel as though they do not
belong to your body.
Your feet, ankles, calves, knees, thighs, waist,
Shoulders, arms, and hands feel as though they do not belong to
your body.
You are now at a deeper, healthier level of mind, deeper than
before. 4.
This is your physical relaxation level 3.
Whenever you mentally repeat and visualize the number 3, your
body will relax as completely as you are now, and more so
every time you practice. practice.
Take another deep breath and as you exhale, mentally repeat and
visualize the number two
three times.
Level 2 is for mental relaxation, where noises will not distract
you. Instead, noises will help you to relax mentally more and
more.
To help you learn to relax mentally at Level 2, I am
going to call your attention to different passive scenes.
Visualizing any scene that makes you tranquil and passive will
help you relax mentally.
Your being at the beach on a nice summer day may be
a tranquil and passive scene for you.
A day out fishing may be a tranquil and passive scene for
you.
A tranquil and passive scene for you may be a walk through
the woods on a beautiful summer day when the breeze is just
right where there are tall shade trees Trees and beautiful
flowers, a very blue sky,
an occasional white cloud, birds singing in the distance, even
squirrels playing on tree limbs, hear the birds singing in the
distance.
This is Mental Relaxation Level 2, where noises will not
distract you.
To enhance mental relaxation at Level 2, practice visualizing
tranquil and passive scenes.
To enter the basic plane level 1, mentally repeat and visualize
the number 1 three times.
You are now at level 1, the basic plane level that you
are able to use for a purpose, any purpose you desire.
To enter deeper, healthier levels of mind, practice with the
Countdown Deepening Exercises.
To deepen, count downward from 100 to 1, or from 50 to
1, or from 25 to 1.
When you reach the count of one, you will have reached a
deeper, healthier level of mind, deeper than before.
You will always have full control and complete dominion over
your faculties and senses at all levels of the mind, including
the outer conscious level.
The best time to practice the countdown deepening exercises is
in the morning when you wake up.
Remain in bed at least five minutes practicing the countdown
deepening exercises.
The second best time to practice is at night when you are
ready to retire. higher.
The third best time to practice is at noon after lunch.
Five minutes of practice is good.
Ten minutes is very good.
And 15 minutes is excellent.
To practice once a day is good, two times a day is
very good, and three times a day is excellent.
If you have a health problem, practice for 15 minutes three
times a day.
To help you enter a deeper, healthier level of mind I am
going to count from 10 to 1
On each descending number you will feel yourself going deeper
and you will enter a deeper, healthier level of mind
Feel going deeper
8, 7, 6, deeper and deeper, 5, 4, 3, deeper and deeper,
2, 1. 1.
You are now at a deeper, healthier level of mind, deeper than
before.
You may enter a deeper, healthier level of mind by simply
relaxing your eyelids.
Relax your eyelids.
Feel how relaxed they are.
Allow this feeling of relaxation to flow slowly downward
throughout your body, all the way down to your toes.
It is a wonderful feeling to be deeply relaxed, a very healthy
state of being.
To help you enter a deeper, healthier level of mind,
I'm going to count from 1 to 3 and cause a sound
with my fingers.
At that moment, you will project yourself mentally to your ideal
place of relaxation.
I will then stop talking to you, and when you next hear
my voice, One hour of time will have elapsed at this level
of mind My voice will not startle you You will take a
deep breath
Relax And go deeper
One
Two
Three Project yourself mentally to your ideal place Of
relaxation Until you hear my voice again Relax.
Relax.
Take a deep breath, and as you exhale, relax and go deeper.
whenever you hear me mention the word relax all unnecessary
movements and activities of your body brain and mind will cease
immediately and you will become completely passive and relaxed
physically and mentally.
The difference between genius mentality and lay mentality is
that geniuses use more of their minds and use them in a
special manner.
You are now able to use more of your mind and to
use it in a special manner.
The following are beneficial statements that you may
occasionally repeat while at these levels of the mind.
Repeat mentally after me.
My increasing mental faculties are for serving humanity better.
Every day, in every way, I am getting better,
better, and better.
positive thoughts bring me benefits and advantages I desire.
I have full control and complete dominion over my sensing
faculties at all levels of the mind,
including the outer conscious levels.
I will always maintain a perfectly healthy body and mind.
Every time you function at these levels of the mind,
you will receive beneficial effects physically and mentally.
You may use these levels of the mind to help yourself physically
and mentally.
You may use these levels of the mind to help your loved
ones physically and mentally.
You may use these levels of the mind to help any human
being who needs help physically and mentally.
You will always use these levels of the mind in a constructive,
creative manner for all that is good, honest, pure, clean, and
positive and this is so
You will continue to take part in constructive and creative
activities
to make this a better world to live in,
so that when we move on,
we shall have left behind a better world for those who follow.
You will consider the whole of humanity,
depending on their ages, as fathers or mothers,
brothers or sisters,
sons or daughters.
You are a superior human being,
You have greater understanding, compassion, and patience with
others.
In a moment, I am going to count from one to five
and cause a sound with my fingers.
At that moment, you will open your eyes, be wide awake, feeling
fine and in perfect health, Feeling Better Than Before
Coming out slowly now.
At the count of five, you will open your eyes, be wide
awake, feeling fine and in perfect health,
feeling better than before, 4.
Feeling the way you feel when you have slept the right amount
of revitalizing, refreshing, relaxing, healthy sleep.
4. 5. Eyes open, wide awake, feeling fine and in perfect health,
feeling better than before.